A. John Woodill

P.O. Box 124 Estes Park, CO 80517 | (858) 210-9667 johnwoodill@gmail.com || http://www.johnwoodill.com

Summary

Economist with experience transforming, visualizing, and modeling data to communicate economic research results. I am an adaptive learner with strong analytical and technical abilities able to communicate results effectively. Willing to take on new situations and tasks independently or as a team member.

Technical Skills

- Economic research background
- Statistical/mathematical methods: Non/Semi/Parametric, Machine/Deep Learning, Bayesian, Dynamic Programming, and Stochastic methods
- Code: R (6 yrs), Python (2 yrs), Stata (2 yrs),
 SQL (1 yr), SAS (1 yr), Matlab (1 yr)
- Tools: Docker, Shiny, Travis CI unit testing, MS Office, Google Drive/Doc/Sheets, LaTeX, Dropbox, git, Stackoverflow, AWS, Google Cloud

Experience

University of Hawaii at Manoa Independent Research Projects

Honolulu, HI Jan 2016 – Current

- Historical Fine Scale Weather Interpolation: Interpolate fine-scale weather data using a relative-anomaly spline interpolation technique for 460,000 grid stations in the contiguous US from 1900-2013.
- Nonlinear Temperature Libraries: Developed R/Python libraries to calculate nonlinear temperature distributions degree days and time in each degree.
- fmlogit Library: Contributed to R library that estimates a fractional multinomial logit by fixing bugs and improving performance.
- Data Science Docker: Custom docker image for processing parallel data analyses and research replication.

University of Hawaii at Manoa

Honolulu, HI

Research Assistant

Jan 2014 – Current

- Research, design, and implement statistical/mathematical models to estimate the impact of an invasive species to Hawaiian coffee, the coffee berry borer.
- Collaborate closely with economic research team, research scientists, coffee farmers, and stakeholders to estimate economic damage to coffee production and optimize decisions to reduce infestation levels.
- Develop tools for farmers to evaluate farm-level decisions to improve economic outcomes and decisions.
- Present research results to local farmers at coffee conferences in Hawaii, UH CBB Coffee Summits, USDA policy makers, and the United Nations Food and Agricultural Organization (UNFAO).

SDSU Social Science Research Laboratory

San Diego, CA 2012

Research Assistant

- Collect, aggregate, transform, and interpret survey data to provide feedback and results on various projects for the university administration.
- Collaborate with local community and business partners to collect survey data and provide analysis to convey event and customer feedback.

Education

University of Hawaii at Manoa <i>Ph.D. Economics</i>	Honolulu, HI 2013 – Current
University of Hawaii at Manoa <i>M.A. Economics</i>	Honolulu, HI 2013 – 2015
San Diego State University B.A. Economics – Quantitative Analysis Summa Cum Laude	San Diego, CA 2010 – 2013